

# MARIA SOROKINA

Frontend developer Russia. Ready to relocate

### **CONTACT ME**

+7 (909) 138-06-66 mashasorokina@inbox.ru LinkedIn: @bijou743 GitHub: @bijou743

### **LANGUAGES**

Russian, English

# **Summary**

I work in web programming more than 10 years. I have 1 year experience as PHP-developer, 3 years experience in Java-development as employee and 7 years experience of web development in my own business. At the beginnig of 2022 I've decided to change my career and work as frontend developer. Now I'm learning new technologies, frameworkds and libraries: JavaScript, SCSS/SASS, VueJS, Pinia, Vue Router, Nuxt, TypeScript, etc.

During my career I've been engaged in the development of new web applications from scratch, as well as working with existing systems with a large set of legacy code. Now I am ready to tasks of any complexity, I'm ready to learn, work and develop.

# **Tools**











SASS/SCSS Tailwind



Bootstrap JavaScript















Vite











GitHub

Figma

Zeplin

Photoshop

# **Soft Skills**

- I'm responsible, disciplined and self-organized
- I am punctual, I value my time and the time of other people
- I am friendly and know how to communicate with people
- I like to work in a team but also I can work on my own and take my own decisions
- I know how to work with documentation and look for information
- I like to learn and put my knowledge into practice
- I'm ready to solve complex tasks

# **Experience**

2014-2022 Fullstack Developer Wheelko - boardgames shop and club

Fullstack developer. I was engaged in the

development and support of the CRM system and online store of board games.

### Responsibilities:

- application architecture development. The application consisted of 2 logical parts: CRM system and online store
- database structure development
- adaptive layout development according to layouts from the designer
- "brining pages to life" with JavaScript and jQuery
- creating backend with Java and OpenCms
- connection of the payment system
- development of interaction with third-party services (for example boardgamegeek.com to download additional information about goods)
- setting up and installing the site on a "live" server
- setting up SSL-certificate
- constant improvements and introduction of new functionality (for example, change of loyalty system, transition to a new website design, etc.)

Using technologies and tools: Java, OpenCms, HTML, CSS, JSP, JavaScript, jQuery, Spring Roo, PostgreSQL, Maven, Figma, Spring Tools

2011 - 2014 Fullstack developer ITDT Ltd. itdt.ru

Fullstack developer. I was involved in the development of existing web applications, desktop applications and participated in the development of web applications from scratch.

### Responsibilities:

- improving of existing web applications according to technical task, creating of new functionality and error correction
- developing of web applications from scratch in a team: layout creating, Javascript writing, creating backend with Java and OpenCms
- improving of desktop application for pawnshop according to technical task, creating of new functionality and error correction
- creating of OpenCms localisation module
- taking part of daily meetings
- learning of new technologies and preparation of reports for colleagues

One of the projects in which creation I took part from scratch is the website for the Contemporary Art Museum Erarta erarta.com.

The website was developed based on OpenCms.

I was the lead developer of this project.

Using technologies and tools: Java, OpenCms, HTML, CSS, JSP, JavaScript, jQuery, Spring Roo, PostgreSQL, Maven, SVN Server, Spring Tools, Eclipse

#### Software center pbprog.ru

I started to work in Software center between the 4th and 5th year of study at the university.

During the work I created a company website on the 1C-Bitrix platform. My responsibilities included developing the site structure, setting up the necessary modules, forms, adding content to the site and customizing existing 1C-Bitrix modules.

Using technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, 1C-Bitrix

## **Education**

2006-2011 Vyatka State University

Master's degreen in "Informatics in econimics". Diploma with honors.

### **Hobbies**

In addition to programming I love cinema, boardgames, cooperative computer games, quizzes, music and travel.